{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does the acronym SMAW stand for?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Shielded Metal Arc Welding",
        "b": "Shielded Magnetic Arc Welding",
        "c": "Strong Magnetic Arc Welding",
        "d": "Solid Metal Arc Welding"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of joint can be made using SMAW welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Butt joint",
        "b": "Lap joint",
        "c": "T-joint ",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
  {
      "question": "What type of electrode is used in SMAW welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Flux-cored",
        "b": "Stick",
        "c": "Wire ",
        "d": "Tungsten "
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What type of power source is used in SMAW welding?  ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "DC",
        "b": "AC ",
        "c": "Both A & B",
        "d": "None of the above "
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the purpose of the flux coating on the electrode in SMAW welding? ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To protect the weld from oxidation",
        "b": "To provide a shielding gas",
        "c": "To improve the mechanical properties of the weld",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What type of metal can be welded using SMAW?  ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Steel",
        "b": "Aluminium",
        "c": "Copper",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the major advantage of SMAW welding?  ",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Speed",
        "b": "Portability",
        "c": "Automation",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "During DC SMAW, which polarity concentrates more heat on the electrode",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Direct Current straight polarity",
        "b": "Direct current reverse polarity",
        "c": "Polarity does not matter"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of groove is constructed for vertical position welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "V shaped groove",
        "b": " No groove",
        "c": "U shaped groove"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following defect can result from using wet or damp electrode?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Lack of fusion",
        "b": "porosity",
        "c": "slag inclusion",
        "d": "Undercut"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
]
}


